University of Connecticut
© 2004 University of Connecticut
University of Connecticut, Committee on Degrees with Distinction Records.
1930-1948.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
University of Connecticut.
1.75 linear feet.
MSS19980263
The collection contains memoranda, minutes, examinations and questions pertaining to the development of a comprehensive examination program at the University of Connecticut for undergraduates culminating in the ability of students to graduate with distinction from their degree programs.
History
In 1931, the faculty of the University of Connecticut voted to offer comprehensive examinations in most degree programs to graduating seniors, and outgrowth of a report to the Committee on the Study of Honors (11/6/1930). The departments reported the results of the examinations and their recommendations to the Registrar and the Committees on Scholastic Standing and Degrees with Distinction. Degrees would then be awarded without distinction, with distinction or with highest distinction.
The program was administered and coordinated by the Registrar's Office in conjunction with the two faculty committees mentioned. It is unclear as to whether the Committee on Degrees with Distinction was independent or associated with the Provost's Office and/or the Faculty Senate. The Committee on Scholastic Standing was, and still is, a permanent committee of the Faculty Senate.
Scope and Content
The collection contains memoranda, minutes, examinations and questions pertaining to the development of a comprehensive examination program at the University of Connecticut for undergraduates.
Arrangement
Series I: Committee Records ( 1930-1948 ) includes correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and examinations (all stages) pertaining to the establishment of a mechanism to award degrees within departments and schools that recognized the intellectual quality of the student. The files are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, faculty, staff and students. See especially, the George S. Torrey Papers, Registrar's Office Records (portions restricted), and University Senate Records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut. Administration.; Connecticut State College.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.
Subjects:
Degrees, Academic--Connecticut.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Administrative Records.; Memoranda.; Minutes.; School Records.; Notes.; Examinations.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Unknown. The possibility exists that these records were transferred to the University Archives as a single unit but associated with any one (or more) of the following collections: George S. Torrey Papers; University Senate Records, President's Office Records, and/or Registrar's Office Records.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Committee Records, 1930-1948
  - 1930-1931 (Box 1:)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - 1932-1933 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - 1936-1937 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - 1939-1940 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 2:, Folder 11)
  - 1941-1942 (Box 2:, Folder 12)
  - 1942-1943 (Box 2:, Folder 13-15)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - 1944-1945 (Box 3:, Folder 17)
  - 1945-1946 (Box 3:, Folder 18)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 3:, Folder 19-21)
  - 1947-1948 (Box 3:, Folder 22)
  - 1947-1948 (Box 4:, Folder 23-24)